[
  {
    "id": 1.0,
    "topic": "Privileges",
    "placeholder": "sudo -s",
    "solution": "sudo -s",
    "question": "open a root shell",
    "level": 1.0
  },
  {
    "id": 2.0,
    "topic": "Privileges",
    "placeholder": "sudo -s -u user",
    "solution": "sudo -s -u user",
    "question": "open a shell as user",
    "level": 1.0
  },
  {
    "id": 3.0,
    "topic": "Privileges",
    "placeholder": "sudo -k",
    "solution": "sudo -k",
    "question": "forget sudo passwords",
    "level": 1.0
  },
  {
    "id": 4.0,
    "topic": "Privileges",
    "placeholder": "sudo visudo",
    "solution": "sudo visudo",
    "question": "edit /etc/sudoers",
    "level": 1.0
  },
  {
    "id": 5.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "apt-get update",
    "solution": "apt-get update",
    "question": "refresh available updates",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 6.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "apt-get upgrade",
    "solution": "apt-get upgrade",
    "question": "upgrade all packages",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 7.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "apt-get dist-upgrade",
    "solution": "apt-get dist-upgrade",
    "question": "upgrade Ubuntu version",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 8.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "apt-get install pkg",
    "solution": "apt-get install pkg",
    "question": "install pkg",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 9.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "apt-get purge pkg",
    "solution": "apt-get purge pkg",
    "question": "uninstall pkg",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 10.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "apt-get autoremove",
    "solution": "apt-get autoremove",
    "question": "remove obsolete packages",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 11.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "apt-get -f install",
    "solution": "apt-get -f install",
    "question": "try to fix broken packages",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 12.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "dpkg --configure -a",
    "solution": "dpkg --configure -a",
    "question": "try to fix broken packages",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 13.0,
    "topic": "Package management",
    "placeholder": "dpkg -i pkg.deb",
    "solution": "dpkg -i pkg.deb",
    "question": "install file pkg.deb",
    "level": 2.0
  },
  {
    "id": 14.0,
    "topic": "System services",
    "placeholder": "/etc/init.d/service start",
    "solution": "/etc/init.d/service start",
    "question": "start service (SysV)",
    "level": 3.0
  },
  {
    "id": 15.0,
    "topic": "System services",
    "placeholder": "/etc/init.d/service stop",
    "solution": "/etc/init.d/service stop",
    "question": "stop service (SysV)",
    "level": 3.0
  },
  {
    "id": 16.0,
    "topic": "System services",
    "placeholder": "/etc/init.d/service status",
    "solution": "/etc/init.d/service status",
    "question": "check service(SysV)",
    "level": 3.0
  },
  {
    "id": 17.0,
    "topic": "System services",
    "placeholder": "/etc/init.d/service restart",
    "solution": "/etc/init.d/service restart",
    "question": "restart service(SysV)",
    "level": 3.0
  },
  {
    "id": 18.0,
    "topic": "Network",
    "placeholder": "ifconfig",
    "solution": "ifconfig",
    "question": "show network information",
    "level": 4.0
  },
  {
    "id": 19.0,
    "topic": "Network",
    "placeholder": "iwconfig",
    "solution": "iwconfig",
    "question": "show wireless information",
    "level": 4.0
  },
  {
    "id": 20.0,
    "topic": "Network",
    "placeholder": "sudo iwlist scan",
    "solution": "sudo iwlist scan",
    "question": "scan for wireless network",
    "level": 4.0
  },
  {
    "id": 21.0,
    "topic": "Network",
    "placeholder": "sudo /etc/init.d/networking restart",
    "solution": "sudo /etc/init.d/networking restart",
    "question": "reset network for manual configurations",
    "level": 4.0
  },
  {
    "id": 22.0,
    "topic": "Network",
    "placeholder": "(file) /etc/network/interfaces",
    "solution": "(file) /etc/network/interfaces",
    "question": "manual configuration ",
    "level": 4.0
  },
  {
    "id": 23.0,
    "topic": "Network",
    "placeholder": "ifup interface",
    "solution": "ifup interface",
    "question": "bring interface online",
    "level": 4.0
  },
  {
    "id": 24.0,
    "topic": "Firewall",
    "placeholder": "ufw enable",
    "solution": "ufw enable",
    "question": "turn on the firewall",
    "level": 5.0
  },
  {
    "id": 25.0,
    "topic": "Firewall",
    "placeholder": "ufw disable",
    "solution": "ufw disable",
    "question": "turn off the firewall",
    "level": 5.0
  },
  {
    "id": 26.0,
    "topic": "Firewall",
    "placeholder": "ufw default allow",
    "solution": "ufw default allow",
    "question": "allow all connections bydefault",
    "level": 5.0
  },
  {
    "id": 27.0,
    "topic": "Firewall",
    "placeholder": "ufw default deny",
    "solution": "ufw default deny",
    "question": "drop all connections bydefault",
    "level": 5.0
  },
  {
    "id": 28.0,
    "topic": "Firewall",
    "placeholder": "ufw status",
    "solution": "ufw status",
    "question": "current status and rules",
    "level": 5.0
  },
  {
    "id": 29.0,
    "topic": "Firewall",
    "placeholder": "ufw allow port",
    "solution": "ufw allow port",
    "question": "allow traffic on port",
    "level": 5.0
  },
  {
    "id": 30.0,
    "topic": "Firewall",
    "placeholder": "ufw deny port",
    "solution": "ufw deny port",
    "question": "block port",
    "level": 5.0
  },
  {
    "id": 31.0,
    "topic": "System",
    "placeholder": "lsb_release -a",
    "solution": "lsb_release -a",
    "question": "get Ubuntu version",
    "level": 6.0
  },
  {
    "id": 32.0,
    "topic": "System",
    "placeholder": "uname -r",
    "solution": "uname -r",
    "question": "get kernel version",
    "level": 6.0
  },
  {
    "id": 0.0,
    "topic": "Privileges",
    "placeholder": "sudo command",
    "solution": "sudo command",
    "question": "run command as root",
    "level": 1.0
  }
]
